Danh Tran

<u>linkedin.com/in/danhtrandev</u> danhtran.dev@outlook.com

About Me

As a software engineer with 6 years of experience, I'm easy to adapt to new tasks, and very patient with new codebases. I'd like to dig into the architecture, optimize the code, spend time debugging, and always think about "How to make it faster?" or "Is this code easy to understand?". Ideally, I hope to develop my career as an Android Engineer. I believe that my contribution to your company will be valuable!

Employment

Senior Software Engineer

ShopBack Group

Mar 2022

Product Earn More & Challenge

- PIC of product Earn More & Challenge on Android Platform. Contribute to the feature ideas, tech design, implementation, and unit test for Android.
- Collaborate with other Tech teams to contribute to technical decisions.
- Tech skills: ViewBinding, DataBinding, MVVM, RxJava, Unit Test, Clean Architecture

Senior Software Engineer

Zalo Group

Apr 2018 - Mar 2022

Product Zalo Chat

- Collaborate with Product Design to define & implement features
- Contribute to restructure Zalo Message Database (for Mobile client) to help users store more messages on their phones but keep the query fast and light.
- In charge of features: Mini Chat, Bubble Chat, Message Notification, Message types: Sticker, Voice, Photo, Doodle Drawing and GIF.
- Tech skills: MVP, MVC, SQLite, C++, Unit Test, Clean Architecture.

Software Engineer

XCT, YOMI Studio, VNG Corp

May 2016 - Apr 2018

- Implement new UI for game events. This game was published in Thai Lan (VNG Corp).
- Build a new Puzzle Game (Brick Breaker type) from scratch. This game was published in US (YOMI Studio).
- Build a new Card Game (Gamble type game) from scratch. This game published in Viet Nam (XCT).
- Maintain the existing codebase and fix the technical problems.
- Tech skills: Unity3D, cocos2dx, C#, C++, MVC.

Education

Viet Nam University Information of Technology

Sep 2012 - Jan 2017

Bachelor's Degree in Software Engineering

Additional Side Project

- **Been Together App**: An Android app can help users track on their love diary. Got over 1 million downloads.
- **KBC Trivial Quiz Game**: A Quiz game for Android user, like "Who wants to be a millionaire?" TV Show. Got over 5 million downloads.

Languages and IDE

- Language: Java, Kotlin, C++, C#, Python, SQLite
- IDE: Visual Studio, Android Studio, VS Code